Marvin Obigwilo

mobig.web@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/marvin-obigwilo

https://marvinobig.github.io/

Summary

Currently a student in the Northcoder's fullstack javaScript bootcamp and set to graduate on September 16th, 2022.

My skills include Git, GitHub, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6), React JS, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB/PostgreSQL & Test Driven Development with Jest

After my first experience with coding, I realized that this is something I enjoyed a lot, being able to have a mixture of creativity and logic and turning an idea into a product/service.

In my spare time, I try to expand and develop my skills as much as I can by completing online courses and carrying out my own projects.

My projects can be viewed on my online portfolio - https://marvinobig.github.io/

Experience

Clarks Stock Assistant

Clarks

Jun 2022 - Present (3 months +)

My responsibilities include managing online orders & deliveries, picking stock for sales members, replenishing stock, and supporting sales members in the stock room.

υρ Web Developer

Upwork

Feb 2022 - Feb 2022 (1 month)

Using a mockup image of a page provided by the client I developed a landing page using HTML, CSS and Javascript for use on their knowledge base software.

Web Developer

Finance

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022 (2 months)

I was tasked with developing a portfolio for a graphic design student who is looking for a way to show off her best projects and the outcomes.

Event Staff

Michael Wisher Team Support

Oct 2018 - Jul 2021 (2 years 10 months)

I poured and served draught beer, ciders, soft drinks & mixes for customers in a fast paced bar environment.

I also looked after the bar environment by keeping it clean and tidy for customers and helped close the bar after the shift. Greeted & welcomed new customers, answered initial questions and served drink & food orders.

Partnered and worked with team members to serve customers. Worked within restaurants to serve food as a waiter.

Education

Northcoders

Computer Software Engineering

May 2022 - Sep 2022

I learned all about the DOM (Document Object Model) and how to make accessible websites with semantic HTML and responsive CSS, and I was also introduced to UX. I was taught how to use react.js in-depth as it is the most in-demand front-end framework. I was then introduced to its key peripheral technologies and taught all about testing front-end applications.

I was taught how to use Node.js to run code for the back end and focused on ways of dealing with asynchronous programming. I created APIs and databases using Express and SQL. I also worked with some pretty cool third-party APIs and deployed applications to the cloud.

Nottingham Trent University

Higher National Diploma, Digital Media Technology

Sep 2018 - Jul 2021

I was taught the fundamentals of writing computer programs, as well as numeracy and web development with HTML, CSS & JavaScript. I developed an understanding of programming for web-based applications, problem analysis and the procedures for program design and I was Introduced to the fundamental principles of SAD (Systems Analysis & Design).

During the period of this course, I have designed and produced both static & dynamic websites suitable for both desktop and mobile platforms. My understanding and awareness of the technological, social and economic factors driving the IT industry were also furthered. I improved my time and project management skills, presentations and report writing skills. Above all, however, the skill of continued professional development and lifelong learning is what I took away from the course.

Matthew Boulton College

BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma, Applied Science

2015 - 2017

This covered topics across biology, chemistry and physics and allowed me to acquire a high level of practical laboratory skills. I built on my previous studies of science in secondary school by widening my knowledge of scientific investigation and practical techniques and developing the numeracy skills required in a scientific setting.

Skills

React.js • JavaScript • Front-End Development • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • HTML • Node.js • Express.js • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Jest